globosapiens.net 2007-10-11

# GLOBOsapiens.net - Privacy Policy

**Overall privacy statement**  
This web site located at www.globosapiens.net in the following called "Web-site" is owned and operated by GLOBOsapiens GmbH. The Web-site is focused on building an online community of avid travelers who can read about and choose travel destinations, plan their trips, share their travel experiences, build their own online gallery and purchase vacation packages from a select group of travel providers. The protection of your privacy is of great importance to us. Our Privacy Statement describes our commitment to protecting your privacy. In order to fully understand your rights related to privacy issues, we encourage you to read this Privacy Statement. As our services evolve, we may from time to time amend this Privacy Statement.  
Please revisit this Privacy Statement periodically and, if you have questions regarding this Privacy Statement, contact us at privacy@globosapiens.net 

**Section 1. Collecting Personal Information.**  
We gather information from our members and visitors primarily through the following ways:  

  * voluntary member registration 
  * member submitted content 
  * cookie technology 
  * IP addresses 

**Voluntary Member Registration**  
When you register as a member, we collect your basic demographic information and general information about yourself. From this information we create a profile that helps us identify the type of '.GLOBOsapiens.net.' experience that is most relevant to you. With this information, we can customize our services and your experience to suit your needs and preferences. At the initial member registration screen we ask for your first name, member user name, password, e-mail address, your mother language, age and gender . This information is required if you register. There is some other information you can provide but which is not mandatory like your interests or your last name. Occasionally, we may also collect additional personal information if you choose to enter a contest or complete a survey form. Once you are a member, we will use the information we receive from you to determine what travel information is most appropriate for you and what information you may find most relevant. We will also use the information we receive from you to determine which of our members would most likely read your submissions. 

**Member Submitted Content**  
Some personal information like member name, hometown, country and other information you choose to submit will become public on the Web-site. Your email adress will never be posted to the public on the Web-site. Contacting you is done by a e-mail form to make sure that your e-mail adress will not get spammed. Anyhow if you choose to contact other members your e-mail adress will be sent to the person you are contacting. This will allow him/her to get in touch with you. 

**Cookie Technology**  
We use "cookies" to track and store your preferences in order to personalize our site for you. A cookie is a small data file that is sent to your browser and is stored on your computer's hard drive when you visit the Web-site. A cookie assigns a random, unique number to your computer. Cookies allow us to recognize members when they come to our Web-site after they initially register. The cookies record "clickstream" information (data reporting the URLs or names of the pages on our site that you have visited) and help us estimate our audience size, determine which areas of our Web-site are the most popular and serve targeted advertising. No advertiser's cookie is ever placed on your computer. Cookies also make your experience easier by saving your preferences and passwords. For example, if you choose "Remember Me" during sign in, we will store a scrambled version of your member ID in a permanent cookie file on your hard drive so that we can track your personalized services and preferences from one visit to the next. Our cookies customize the Web-site and allow our members and guides to easily update their information. We do not allow anyone else to access your cookie. A cookie cannot read data off of your hard drive or read cookie files created by other web sites. You can reject cookies by turning them off in your browser. This will, however, prevent you from using our customized services, may limit system performance and may cause certain features of the Web-site to malfunction or not work at all. You may also have to repeatedly enter personal information in order to participate in various services or promotions. 

**IP Addresses**  
An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer automatically when you access the Internet. When you visit a particular page on our Web-site, register or login our servers record your IP address. We may record IP addresses in order to facilitate systems administration or to report aggregate information to our advertisers (e.g., how many visitors logged on to our Web-site). 

**Section 2. Children's Personal Information.**  
We do not intend to collect personal information from children under 13 years of age. If we learn that we have inadvertently collected individually identifying information from a child under the age of 13, such as full name, home address, e-mail address, telephone number or any other information that would allow someone to identify or contact the child, we will promptly delete that data from our systems. 

**Section 3. Use of Personal Information.**  
Globosapiens.net uses your personal information in the following three ways: 

  * To customize our services and your experience 
  * To serve targeted advertising 
  * To send you optional e-mail messages 

**Customized Services and Experiences**  
We gather information from members in order to provide them with personalized experiences. Every time you visit our Web-site, we provide you with what we believe will be your preferred topics, the content that will be most relevant for you, and services that will be of the most interest to you. 

**Targeted Advertising**  
In order to bring you offers that may be of interest to you, and to help finance the cost of making our Web-site available to you, we place advertisements on our Web-site. Gathering information from members allows us to target advertisements and sponsorships. We believe this makes information on our Web-site more relevant to you and is more productive for our advertisers. For example, if you have indicated that you enjoy running, we can target an advertisement to you about a special deal on running shoes. It is important to note that we do not share your personal information with advertisers, but we may share it with ad servers acting on our behalf who place advertisements on our Web-site for us. We, and any third-party ad servers acting on our behalf, act as the middlemen between you and the advertisers who want to reach you. Our third-party ad servers are also bound by the terms of this Privacy Statement. 

**Optional E-mail Messages**  
When you register with our site and indicate you would like to receive e-mails newsletters occasionally we may send you e-mail messages containing information regarding changes to our site to keep you informed and with information and special travel deals related to our services, or third-party products that you may find interesting. If you elect to receive such e-mails when you register, you may update your profile at any time afterwards to discontinue such mailings. You can update your member profile and/or opt out of receiving e-mails in your account menu after you login. 

**Section 4. Sharing of Personal Information.**  
As a general rule, we will not disclose your personal information to third parties, except to the extent necessary to provide you with a requested service or under circumstances required by law. We will disclose your personal information when we believe in good faith that any applicable law, regulation, or legal process requires it, or when we believe disclosure is necessary to protect or enforce our rights or the rights of another member. We will use, or supply to others, aggregated data (independent of any personal identifiers) for research and commercial purposes, such as describing our services, members and guides to prospective partners, advertisers and other third parties. These data are pooled and stripped of personal identifying information and cannot be traced to you specifically. 

Specific uses of personal information that vary from this Privacy Statement (if any) may be found in the privacy statement applicable to a specific service provided by our Web-site (e.g., a contest or survey). When you are notified that your personal information will be used in a manner that varies from those described in this Privacy Statement, the use of your personal information will be subject to the notification for that particular service, such as with sweepstakes, contests or promotions. Please look for privacy statements that apply to the services in which you participate. It is important to note that we do not control the privacy policies of our advertisers and other third-party web sites for which we provide advertisements and links. If you click through an advertisement or link to and submit your information to an advertiser or to another web site, you will be subject to that advertiser's or web site's privacy policies, if any. We do not assume responsibility or liability for such third-parties' policies or actions. 

**Section 5. Controlling the Use of Your Personal Information.**  
You can reject cookies by disabling them in your browser or you can configure your browser to alert you when cookies are sent. If you register with our Web-site and provide us with personal information, you will always have the option at any time to cancel your registration. Canceling your account will remove your personal information from our systems. We reserve the right to maintain information about registered members who violate whose access to the Web-site has been denied, in order to detect repeat offenders. 

**Section 6. More About Your Privacy**  
You should be aware that personal information you voluntarily disclose online in a public area might be collected and used by others. We do not control all actions of visitors or members. Your disclosure of personal information in a travel submission, an interactive question and answer, or any other publicly-accessible place on our Web-site is done so at your own risk. You should understand that your personal information might be collected and used by others to send you advertisements or unsolicited messages or for other purposes. In this case pleas do contact our stuff at privacy@globosapiens.net and do not reply to this e-mail in any case. As long as you do not reply your e-mail adress is unknown. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and should be careful when disclosing your personal information online. 

While we will take appropriate security measures to protect the privacy of your personal information, no protection is foolproof, and transmissions made over the Internet cannot be made absolutely secure. We do not assume any liability for disclosure of data resulting from errors in transmission or made by unauthorized third parties. 

**Section 7. Acceptance of Privacy Statement.**  
By using the Globosapiens.net Web-site and services, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Statement. If you do not agree or are not comfortable with any part of this Privacy Statement, you should no longer use our Web-site. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time. Your continued use of any portion of our Web-site following notification or posting of such changes will constitute your acceptance of those changes. 

**Section 8. Contacting Us.**  
If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Statement please contact us at privacy@globosapiens.net. 

_Updated July 2002_

Please do also read our [Terms And Conditions](http://www.globosapiens.net/about/090000.html "Terms And Conditions")
